

# Hvderabad, India

□ (+91) 9515906959 | 
□ rahulmora007@gmail.com | 
□ rahul mora

# **Summary**

A Computer Science graduate with 1year 10months years of experience in the field of back end software development. Currently working as Soft- ware Development Engineer in JP Morgan Chase & Co in the field of reconciliation systems especially handling large volume files. Customer-oriented and structured method of working, focused on quality and maintainability. High motivated to work in team, both comfortable to big companies as in small teams.

### Skills

**Programming Languages** Java C, Python, Javascript

Frameworks And Libraries Spring -boot, Spring Batch, Angular, Node JS, Flask **Databases** MySql, Oracle, No-Sql databases like MongoDB

Tools Cloud Foundry, Kubernetes, Pentaho ETL tool, CI/CD(Jenkins), Jasper Reporting Tool

## **Education**

#### Chaitanya Bharathi Institute Of Technology Hyderabad

CRIT

BTECH IN COMPUTER SCIENCE (CSE)

August 2016 - July 2020

• CGPA - 7.25

# Work Experience \_\_

#### JPMorgan Chase & Co Hyderabad, India

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER

Aug. 2020 - Present

- Developed an Excel file row-by-row Parser to read and process large excel files efficiently
- Innovated the report generation process of our system which increased efficiency by 4 times
- Learnt standard coding practices to write reusable code
- Worked on ETL tools like Pentaho
- Worked on Reporting tools like Jasper Soft
- · Worked on Job scheduling tools like control-m which are used to build loosely coupled components
- Have been exposed to modern cloud technologies like Cloud foundry and Kubernetes
- Gained experience in handling large data and files efficiently & effectively
- Exposed to writing Automatic testing suites

#### JPMorgan Chase & Co

Hyderabad, India Jan. 2020 - Jul. 2020

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER INTERN

- Part of a team which builds reconciliation systems
- Developed an Angular & springboot application to track the reconciliation process
- Developed a spring batch application to load huge files into the Database
- Understood the impact of Agile methodology and the tools like JIRA, confluence
- · Understood the impact of unit test cases and also worked on writing unit test cases for several applications to understand their functionalities

Caravel AI Hyderabad, India

**CONTENT STRATEGIST INTERN** 

May. 2019 - June. 2019

· Caravel AI has an online learning platform called Keats. For keats, I Worked as a content writer for Data science course

### **Achievements**

- Recognized by the technical head of the sub-lob for my efforts in scaling up the application by 4 times
- Stood Third in a Hackathon conducted by Women Techmakers Orgaization

RAHUL RESUME